# **Houngue Yaovi Fiacre**

Alberta, Canada

hfyaovi@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/houngueyaovi github.com/hyaovi

Highly skilled front-end developer with 5 years dedicated in developing and implementing front-end architectures that make pages load faster and keep users engaged. I am good at teaming up with backend folks to blend user interface with server magic. I also dabble in backend development using Node.js and Django/python.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### **Frontend Developer**

July 2020 – to present

Devar

- Co-implemented the successful refactoring of the client-side web architecture to introduce a reliable Progressive Web App (PWA).
- Identified and resolved performance and scalability issues resulting in a notable enhancement of UX and an impressive 35% improvement in page load speed, consequently increasing user engagement.
- Contributed to Research and development efforts and built several libraries and components using Vanilla JavaScript, Browser APIs, and WASM.
- Provided occasional client support to ensure customer satisfaction and product utilization

Web developer April 2018 – July 2020

Freelance

- Rebuilt a tour agency website using React and Next.js, optimizing performance, page loading and user experience.
- Developed over 10 interactive web applications utilizing advanced JavaScript libraries, WordPress and APIs
- Designed and deployed a Progressive Web App (PWA) prototype for a real estate startup utilizing React and MongoDB.
- Completed projects on time and delivered to clients accordingly.

## Front-end developer, Intern

September 2019 – October 2019

Nordclan

- Resolved bugs and implemented new features within an internal bug tracker app constructed with React.
- Collaborated on the transformation of the company's website from PHP/HTML/CSS to a robust Single Page Application (SPA) utilizing React, Redux, and TypeScript, incorporating server-side rendering for SEO optimization.

#### **EDUCATION**

### Master's degree in Applied informatics

Moscow Power Engineering Institute

2020 – 2022

### **Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering**

Kazan National Research Technological University

2012 - 2017

**SKILLS** 

Programming Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript (ES6+), TypeScript, SCSS, and Python3.

**Frameworks/Libraries:** React.js, Redux, Typescript, Next.js, Vue.js, Nuxt.js, Node.js, Express, Git, Webpack, Rollup, RESTful APIs, Docker, Problem Solving.

**Design Tools:** Figma, Adobe XD, Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator.

Soft skills: Team Collaboration, Problem Solving, Continuous Learning, Time Management.

Languages: English, French, Russian.